Guide to the Rose Goldsen papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
Goldsen, Rose papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
- Series IX. Audio Tapes
  - Reel to Reel Tapes
    - New Delivery Systems: Pay Per View* [script: "Cable systems"], 11/7, 11/8/81, 5531
    - A New Kind of TV: Interview with Jim Teicher* [script: 1/19/80], 1/82, 5532
    - Videotex - Prestel* [script: 8/4/79], 2/22/82, 5533
    - Interactive Cable*, 3/12/82, 5534 (cut 1 of 2)
    - Computers and Politics, 6/82, 5535 (cut 1 of 2)
    - TV Ads, 6/82, 5535 (cut 2 of 2)
    - Oh, Those Too Loud Commercials!* [script: 11/8/82], 6/82, 5536 (cut 1 of 2)
    - Networks Vie for More Advertising Time, 6/82, 5536 (cut 2 of 2)
    - Campaign '82: Money Talks But Doesn't Reason* [script = draft], 11/14/82, 5537
    - Video Games* [script: 12/6/82], 12/26/82, 5538
    - DBS in 1984*, 1/16/83, 5539
    - Cable Networks* [script: 2/7/83], 3/6/83, 5540
    - Video Games for Tots* [script: 2/20/83], 3/13/83, 5541
    - Entertainment Suicide* [script: 3/14/83], 4/3/83, 5542
    - Teletext Pilot Studies* [3 3/4 ips; script: 11/1/82], 4/4/83, 5543
    - Electronic Box Office* [script: "Pay Per View" 5/2/82], 4/25, 5/16/83, 5544
    - Disney Channel* [script: 4/25/83], 5/2/83, 5545
    - Games and Subtexts*, 5/22/83, 5546
    - G.I. Joe* [script: "The Littlest Arms Race"], 6/5/83, 5547
    - Next Generation Video Games*, 6/20/83, 5548
    - Cable Bill S66*, 6/27/83, 5549
    - Executive Limo* [script: 7/3/81], 7/4/83, 5550
    - C-Span*, 7/11/83, 5551
    - Teledelivery*, 7/18/83, 5552
    - Dallas Revisited - version A*, 7/24/83, 5553
    - Dallas Revisited - version B*, 7/24/83, 5554
    - TV's Investigative Reporters*, 8/1/83, 5555
    - Tunnel Vision* [script: 3/21/83], 8/8/83, 5556
    - Portable Telephones* [script: 10/9/83], 8/10/83, 5557
    - Testimony of the Stars* [script: 11/29/82], 8/15/83, 5558
    - The Loud Family Again*, 9/5/83, 5559
    - Hackers as Role Models, 10/16, 10/17/83, 5560
    - News From Grenada*, 11/14/83, 5561
    - Computer Games*, 12/12/83, 5562
    - A Christmas Story* [script: "A Modern Nativity Story" 12/22/79], 12/26/83, 5563
    - Stimutech and Subliminals, 1/2/84, 5564
    - The Day After* [script: 11/20/83], 11/21/84, 5565
    - Cable TV, no date, 5566
    - Commercials as Parables, no date, 5567 (cut 1 of 2)
    - Home VCR's, no date, 5567 (cut 2 of 2)
    - Electronic Publishing, no date, 5471 (cut 2 of 2)
    - Fireman, Fireman - electronic games, no date, 5534 (cut 2 of 3)
    - TV in South Africa, no date, 5534 (cut 3 of 3)
    - RKG broadcast - unidentified, no date, 5568
  - Miscellaneous Recordings (not form RKG radio programs)
    - Colin Turnbull lecture [3 3/4 ips], 10/25/73, 5569
    - Primetime TV: The Decision Makers - ABC Closeup - 45" of 60" [tape begins at 7 1/2 ips, then drops to 1 7/8], no date, 5570
    - CATV discussion - 60 Minutes (CBS) [1 7/8 ips], 9/15/70, 5571
    - All About TV - WNYC-TV. New York City - program on soap operas, part 1 of 2, 3/2/76, 6685
    - All About TV - soap operas, part 2 of 2 - interview with RKG, 3/2/76, 6686
  - A record of the folling RKG radio programs has been preserved, but the tapes are missing or were inaudible:
    - Family Images of Prime Time TV, 2/18/74 WVBR, 2/15/75 WHCU
    - Talk Shows and Family Socialization [RKG and Nicholas Tavuchis], 9/7, 9/9/74
    - Policy Paper, 10/24/74
    - Real People Commercials, 11/9, 11/11/74
    - Program on Public Access TV - Interview with Mary Richards, 6/14, 6/21, 6/28/77
    - Upstaging the Constitution, 7/2/77
    - Right Brain, Left Brain - Market Research, 11/11, 11/14/78; 6/2/79
    - Porno, 9/15, 9/16/79
    - Godzilla Update, 10/14/79
    - Embassy Takeover Iran, 11/24, 11/25/79
  - Cassette Tapes
    - Personal Perspective [on Broadcasting], WHCU broadcasts: "Introduction" 6/9/73; "$ spent on commercials vs. programs" 6/14/73; 3-1/2 hours of Saturday morning TV watching" 6/23/73, 5572a
    - Blowing the Whistle on Broadcasting: "Baby Porno" Saturday 9/29 [5/7/77], 5573a
    - Blowing the Whistle on Broadcasting: "The Presidential Campaign: Non-Voting 'Unimportant'" [5/31/80]; "Strawberry Shortcake and Friends" [4/18/81], 5574a
    - Blowing the Whistle on Broadcasting: "Animations" 8/10/80; Laughtracks (1)" 8/17/80; "Laughtracks (2)" 8/24/80, 5575a
    - Blowing the Whistle on Broadcasting: "Subliminal Ads" 5/2-3/81, 5576a
    - Blowing the Whistle on Broadcasting: "Programmed Learning: SRA" n.d.; "Hole in Space" 5/9-10/81, 5577a
    - Juventud y Rebelde-calle prado frente al capitolio nacional, Jacinto Granda, dir. 5/5/72, 5578a
    - Father Philip Bourret [w/RKG], 5/5/72, 5579a
    - Letter to RKG from Jorge Luiz Puerta and Azriel Bibliowic, end of November 1972, RKG letter to them., 5580a
    - Armand Mattelart, RKG-Lima, 12/1/72, 5581a
    - RKG lecture: Broadcasting appearing in newspapers, 1/23/73, 5582a
    - RKG letters (dictation), 1/29/73, 5583a
    - RKG lecture on statutes regulating broadcasting in US, 2/14/73, 5584a
    - RKG comments on Act Film- "The Shell Game-Now You See It, Now You Don't," 2/28/73, 5585a
    - RKG class on Fairness Doctrine, 3/5/73, 5586a
    - RKG talks to Nelson Bingham-Psych seminar on TV paradigm, 3/8/73, 5587a
    - RKG public lectures at ICODES and at Tadeo Lozano 3/20 and, 3/21/73, 5588a
    - ICODES Bogota; RKG public lecture, 3/22/73; panel Bibliowicz, Tvar, Insuasty, 3/27/73, 5589a
    - RKG lecture: Meaning resides in context, 4/4/73, 5590a
    - RKG lecture: Meaning resides in context (side 1). Harold Kohn letter (side 2), 5/11/73, 5591a
    - Roundtable discussion on broadcast journalism: "Behind the First Amendment" 5/73, at Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. WNET-TV program production, WCNY-TV Ch. 24 broadcast 5/29/73, 5592a
    - Gabriela Samper, Tompkins County Airport, 6/14/73, 5593a
    - Johnson Art Museum with Cohen family, 6/23/73, 5594a
    - SSSP panel: An American Family (Craig Gilber, RKG and others) 8/27/73, 5595a
    - Barbara Hall travel take with RKG-Amazon, for [WHCU broadcast] 9/8/73, 5596a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: Status as circuitry of social map 9/25/73, 5597a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: Metabolism of ideas and language in your habitat, 9/27/73, 5598a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: Property of individual vs. property of system, 10/2/73, 5599a
    - RKG lecture: Public Opinions-"Culture Power," Philadelphia, 10/8/73, 5600a
    - RKG Women's Studies lecture, Spring 1974, 5601a
    - WVBR Response to RKG's Analysis of Sesame Street, 3/74, 5602a
    - WVBR panel: Julie Frederikse, Azriel Bibliowicz, and RKG, 3/18/74, about 1 hour, 5603a
    - Gariela Samper on Rest of News, 6/4/74, 5604a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: Paradigm, Bunraku; George Wald, Charles Luce, 9/10/74, 5605a
    - RKG lecture: Paradigm; and on explanation- causality is not linear, 9/12/74, 5606a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: Status/role (dogs vs. humans), 10/1/74, 5607a
    - RKG lectures: Organization of experience 11/5/74; Auto as exoskeleton 10/24/74; Learning how to learn 10/31/74, 5608a
    - RKG talk to Southern Tier School Board: Engineering of children, 11/21/74, 5609a
    - RKG lecture: Women as depicted on TV, Ithaca College 2/5/75, 5610a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: TV - mass desensitization, 2/5/76, 5611a
    - RKG and others: Round table on First Amendment, 2/14/76, 56123
    - RKG lecture in Bogota, Colombia, at weekend conference sponsored by Institute Colombo American & Cafam, 4/3/76, 5613a
    - RKG Soc. 262 lecture: On educational technology, 4/8/76, 5614a
    - RKG talk to Ithaca High School, Daily life in the depression, 56153
    - RKG, Sage Chapel Convocation, Sunday 3/25/79, 5616a
    - RKG vs. Robert Fowler, NYU Media Ecology Conference 4/28/79 - part I, 5617a
    - RKG vs. Robert Fowler, NYU Media Ecology Conference 4/28/79 - part II, 5618a
    - Cuba tour 4/30-5/7/82: Street sounds, RKG comments; discussion on Radio Havana Cuba w/ Jose Pardo, Pedro Martinez: Union de Periodistas, Jose A. Benitez, Gabriel Molina, 5/4/82, 5619a
    - RKG lecture at Utah State University, Logan, Utah; RKG in Barcelona 6/18/82, 5620a
    - Excerpts from Harold [Kohn]'s tape to Gert, 12/27/83, 5621a
    - RKG lecture: "Television's Role in Consciousness Formation," Cornell Media Services recording, n.d., 5622a
  - Tapes Produced By Radio Stations, Etc.
    - Hugh Downs and Harvey Wheeler, MASS MEDIA AND THE FUTURE, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions [CSDI], Santa Barbara, 28:30 rain, rec'd 1/3/73, 5623a
    - John W. Macy, Jr., THE RISE AND FALL OF PUBLIC BROADCASTING, CSDI, 29:07 min, rec'd 6/73, 5624a
    - THE HEART OF THE MATTER - LICENSING - Broadcast ii the First Amendment - I, CSDI, 28:03 min, rec'd 6/, 5625a
    - HOW GOOD IS TELEVISION NEWS REPORTING? - Broadcasting and the First Amendment - II, CSDI, 28:45 min, rec 6/22/73, 5626a
    - WHITEHEAD EMANCIPATION PROCLAMATION - Broadcasting the First Amendment - III, CSDI, 27:54 min, rec'd, 5627a
    - THE NATIONAL NEWS COUNCIL A SOLUTION? - Broadcast and the First Amendment - IV, CSDI, 27:51 min, rec 6/73, 5628a
    - THE RIGHT TO BE UNFAIR - Broadcasting and the First Amendment - V, CSDI, 27:57 min, rec'd 6/73, 5629a
    - CENSORSHIP BY MANIPULATION - Broadcasting and the First Amendment - VI, CSDI, 27:15 m:Ln, rec'd 6/73, 5630a
    - NATIONAL NEWS, LOCAL CONTROL - Broadcasting and the First Amendment - VII, CSDI, 27:26 min, rec'd 6/71, 5631a
    - TELEVISION: THE EXCLUSIVE MEDIUM - Broadcasting and the First Amendment - VIII, CSDI, 27:22 min, rec'd 6/1, 5632a
    - Neil Jacoby, CAN TECHNOLOGY BE NEUTRAL?, CSDI, 40: min, rec'd 5/12/73, 5633a
    - FEEDBACK I: INTRODUCTION TO TV AS A MEDIUM, Pacifica Tape Library, Berkeley, 36:40 min, rec'd 2/1/73, 5634a
    - FEEDBACK II: THE IMAGE EMPIRE, Pacifica Tape Libra Berkeley, 49:55 min, rec'd 2/:./73, 5635a
    - FEEDBACK III: THE FOURTH NETWORK, Pacifica Tape Berkeley, 53:59 min., rec'd 2/1/73, 5636a
    - FEEDBACK IV: A CULTURAL CRITIQUE OF BROADCAST JOURNALISM, Pacifica Tape Library, Berkeley, 47:3f rec'd 2/1/73, 5637a
    - FEEDBACK V: A CULTURAL CRITIQUE OF BROADCAST ENTERTAINMENT, Pacifica Tape Library, Berkeley, 68 min., rec'd 2/1/73, 5638a
    - "INFORMED SOURCES SAID" - A chronology of events from the day of the Watergate break-in, 6/17/72 to the opening day of the Watergate Hearings on 5/17/73, Pacifica Tape Library, Berkeley, 96 min, reel l, 5639a
    - "INFORMED SOURCES SAID," Pacifies Tape Library, Berkeley, 96 min, reel 2, 5640a
    - AMERICA AS ADVERTISED - A documentary "Who's Who of the first phase of the Senate Watergate Hearings; 5/17-8/7/73, Pacifica Tape Library, Berkeley, 133 min, reel 1, 5641a
    - AMERICA AS ADVERTISED, Pacifies Tape Library, Berkeley reel 2, 56423
    - JACK ANDERSON'S IM-" PRESS "-IONS ON WATERGATE, speech a University of Minnesota, 5/21/73, Pacifica Tape Library Berkeley, 88 min., 5643a
    - The Press and Watergate, WCNY-TV, Syracuse, 11/11/73, 56443
    - Script for "Gender Advertising" (slide show), 5645a
    - GAME AND QUIZ SHOWS: DOUBLE YOUR MONEY, DOUBLE YOUR FUN, Pacifies Tape Library, Berkeley, 1975, 58 min., 5646a
    - WTKO 5/20/70 (1 of 2), 5647a
    - WTKO 5/20/70 (2 of 2), 5648a
    - Clay T. Whitehesd - Firing Line (interview by William F. Buckley), PBS 2/24/73, 56493
    - Film - Action for Children's Television - soundtrack, 2/26/73, 56503
    - Reynaldo's tape - Prof. Petrie lecture on general systems theory, 3/73, 56513
    - Ed Bsumeister, "The Liveliest Wire," WCNY-TV, Syracuse 3/6/73, 56523
    - Pastore hearings on public tv - third day, 3/30/73, 56533
    - Shamberg, Top Value TV - 1972 Republican and Democratic presidential conventions (Miami Beach), 4/16/73, 56543
    - Bloomington, Indians - Audio-Visusl Film on Cable TV, 4/16/73 (1 of 2), 56553
    - Bloomington, Indiana - Audio-Visual Film on Cable TV, 4/16/73 - for Soc 262 (2 of 2), 5656a
    - "You and the Commercial" (CBS documentary) 4/26/73, 5657a
    - Watergate - Jack Anderson, Richard Nixon, 4/30/73, 5658a
    - America '73 - 1 hour program on press subpeonas to newsmen. NPACT. Channel 8, Scranton, 5/9/73, 5659a
    - Nicholas Johnson, Address to symposium on mass media, Bucknell University, 11/2/73, 5660a
    - Pastore subcommittee hearings 1/30/74, 5661a
    - John Hess, American Food Disaster (lecture), Cornell, 5/6/74, 5662a
    - Children's TV; Voice of Authority (2 programs - Rest of the News), 7/74, 5663a
    - A.C. Nielsen interview, Tomorrow Show, 8/2/74, 5664a
    - CBS documentary on payola in record industry, 8/11/74, 5665a
    - Julian Jaynes, NYU Media Ecology Conference, Saugerties, NY, 4/29/79, 5666a
    - Media Course, 2/14/82, 5667a
    - Sandra Boddie interview, Geraldo Rivera Show, ABC, 2/17/82, 56683
    - Washington School Media Course - Nan Rubin (NFCB), Ardes Slobodow (PWN), Jean Rice, Lou Bransford (PSSC), 3/3/82, 56693
    - Commercials - recorded off the air, 9/18/74, 56703
    - "Building Democratic Communications," UDC conference, Philadelphia, 11/12/82 - pop culture, 5950a
    - "Building Democratic Communications," UDC conference, Philadelphia, 11/13/82 - Alternative Uses of Computers Community Organizations, 5951a